Sigrid Benezra

sigrid@norwestagency.com | (206) 499-8155 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sdbenezra

Summary

Four years of experience in software engineering, designing and developing secure web applications and distributed backend services at scale using multiple programming languages and AWS services. Served as a mentor supporting the participation and advancement of more women and underrepresented folks in tech. Extensive business management and accounting experience.

Skills

Typescript, React, Python, Java, Javascript, GraphQL, SQL, HTML, CSS, CDK, Distributed Systems, DevOps, Git, Jira, AWS API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, S3, SQS, SNS, Cloudformation, Cloudwatch.

Experience

Sabbatical May 2023 - Current

Amazon/AWS - Software Development Engineer

2019 - April 2023

Seattle, WA

- Prepared architectural design docs and led design review meetings with multiple teams/stakeholders.
- Collaborated with several teams to launch a new platform providing AWS sales personnel access to multiple sales applications through a single interface.
- Developed and maintained backend APIs and frontend code using Java, Javascript, Typescript, and React for a web application serving thousands of internal sales team customers daily.
- Maintained data pipelines with 37 ETL transformation jobs written in Python.
- Mentored junior developers and interns.
- Experienced with both Agile/Scrum and Kanban workflows.

Norwest Insurance Agency - Agency Founder/Operations Manager Seattle, WA

2008-2019

- Co-owner/manager of a personal lines insurance agency. Developed and implemented a business strategy to grow agency profit by 36% over five years.
- Designed agency management and accounting systems, including customization of Salesforce CRM software and workflows.
- Trained employees on the use of agency management software and provided IT support.
- Managed payroll, HR, and financial processes.
- Provided efficient and effective client service and communications, preparing and presenting quote proposals and policy information.
- Initiated and maintained vendor relationships.

InsuranceMart Insurance Agency - Operations/Technical Manager Anchorage, AK

2000-2008

- Co-owner/manager of a personal lines insurance agency with multiple locations.
- Created and maintained a cloud-based database to centralize quote information and efficiently distribute workload among multiple offices.
- Leveraged cloud database to create a system to track sales closing ratios for all agents and locations, enabling the creation of incentive programs to increase sales.
- Instituted accounting procedures and supervised and trained employees on accounting procedures and agency management systems.

Education

Ada Developers Academy - full-stack web development **Excelsior College** - BA Accounting

Community

The Foundation For Sephardic Camp - Executive board member, Treasurer

- Oversight and management of a \$500,000 annual budget
- Financial advisor to Executive Director
- Prepare and present financial reporting at bi-monthly board meetings